1) Find out how many managers there are without listing them. 
3.

SELECT COUNT(emp.job) AS Manager_Count
FROM emp
WHERE job = 'MANAGER';
 
2) Compute the average annual salary + commission for all 
salesman

SELECT AVG(emp.sal + emp.comm)*12 AS Salesman_average_annual_salary_commission
FROM emp
WHERE job = 'SALESMAN';
 
3) Find the highest and lowest paid employees and the difference 
between them

Max -

SELECT ename, sal
FROM emp
WHERE sal = (
    SELECT max(sal)
    FROM emp);

Min -

SELECT ename, sal
FROM emp
WHERE sal = (
        SELECT MIN(sal)
        FROM emp)
;

Difference -

SELECT MAX(sal) - MIN(sal) 
FROM emp;
 
4) Find the number of characters in the longest department name

SELECT DISTINCT dept.dname, LENGTH(dept.dname)
FROM emp
INNER JOIN dept
ON emp.deptno = dept.deptno
WHERE LENGTH(dept.dname) = (
        SELECT MAX(LENGTH(dept.dname))
        FROM dept)
;


 
5) Count the number of people in department 30 who receive 
a salary and the number of people who receive a commission

Salary - 

SELECT COUNT(sal)
FROM emp
WHERE deptno = 30;

Commission -

SELECT COUNT(comm)
FROM emp
WHERE deptno = 30
;

 
6) List the average commission of employees who receive a 
commission and the average commission of all employees (treating 
employees who do not receive a commission as receiving a zero 
commission)


Average commission -

SELECT AVG(comm)
FROM emp;

average commission (Null as 0) -

SELECT AVG(nvl(comm,0))
FROM emp;

 
7) List the average salary of employees that receive a salary, 
the average commission of employees that receive a commission, 
the average salary plus commission of only those employees that 
receive a commission and average salary plus commission of all 
employees including those who do not receive a commission



average salary -

SELECT ROUND(AVG(sal), 2) 
FROM emp;

average commission -

SELECT ROUND(AVG(comm), 2) 
FROM emp;

average salary + commission (Only including those who did receive commission)

SELECT ROUND(AVG(sal+comm), 2) 
FROM emp;

average salary + commission (including those who do not receive a commission)

SELECT AVG(sal + nvl(comm, 0))
FROM emp;
 
8) Compute the daily and hourly salaries for employees 
in department 30. Round the results to the nearest penny. Assume 
there are 22 working days in a month and 8 working hours in a day.

22 working days

SELECT ROUND(SUM(sal)/22, 2)
FROM emp
WHERE deptno = 30;

8 working hours in a day.

SELECT ROUND((SUM(sal)/22)/8, 2)
FROM emp
WHERE deptno = 30;

 
9) Issue the same query as the previous one except that this time 
truncate (trunc) to the nearest penny rather than round.

SELECT TRUNC((SUM(sal)/22)/8, 2)
FROM emp
WHERE deptno = 30;
© 2022 GitHub, Inc.
Terms
Privacy
Security
Status
